http://www.rescuetech1.com/privacy-policy.aspx

5% Discount on orders over $100
Clearance - 15% OFFNew ProductsOVERSTOCKRUTH LEE MANIKINSSLING-LINKAscendersBags, Packs, and BackpacksBeltsBooks, VideosCarabiners & LinksCommunicationConfined Space RescueD2 Escape KitDescenders, Belay DevicesDisaster ManagementEdge ProtectionEMSEscape Kits / RIT RopesFall ProtectionFire RescueFire Training SimulationGlovesHarnessesHelmetsIce RescueIncident CommandKitsKnives & ToolsLightsPadsPromotionalPulleysRigging HardwareRopeRope AccessRope AccessoriesRope RescueRope, CordsRope, Industrial LifelineSlings / LanyardsStretchersSupplied AirTactical Rescue EquipmentTraining Manikins, etc.Trauma KitsTripods and MultipodsVentilationWater Rescue EquipmentWater SafetyWebbingComponentsArborist EquipmentChallenge CourseCMI-GEARGSA Contract Items
Select ...
303
ABTECH
ACR Electronics
Air Systems
Alan Madison Productions
Alliance Fire & Rescue
Alta
Angel Guard
PRIVACY POLICY
Rescue Technology is committed to all aspects of data protection and takes your security seriously.
In order to serve the interests of our customers, it is necessary that we collect some personal data, usually within a business context. Rescue Technology treats all data which identifies an individual or when combined with any other information identifies an individual as Personal Data.
Unless otherwise stated, Rescue Technology will be what’s known as the ‘Controller’ of the personal data you provide to us, this means we control what happens to the data in our possession.
Rescue Technology collects various personal data which may include but is not limited to name, address, email, phone number, IP address, job title.
We need to know your personal data to provide you with information associated with our other services and to stay in touch in future. We will not collect any personal data from you unless it is required for the service.
All the personal data we process is processed by Rescue Technology.
We will endeavor to provide details of the processing locations where possible at the data collection point.
Data which is directly processed by Rescue Technology is located on servers within the USA.
Newsletter and other mailing list data is processed via third party software, MailChimp which is located in the USA.
We may share your data following an enquiry with a limited number of trusted third parties within your region of the globe to enable the maximum service possible.
No other 3rd parties have access to your personal data unless you specifically agree to this sharing of your data in advance.
DATA RETENTION
All details provided will be held in line with legal and contractual requirements unless otherwise stated at the point of collection as below.
The United States Internal Revenue Service requires retention of accounting information for a period of 7 years.
As such, all personal details of customers will be retained by Rescue Technology for a period of 7 years following the settlement of your last invoice, and through the end of that year.
This information may include but is not limited to name, address, email, phone number, IP address, job title, interests along with billing information including any personal data contained within invoices, delivery notes and accounting.
Rescue Technology will attempt to respond to all contact including enquiries in a timely and professional manner.
Any enquiries or other contact which contains personal data will be retained for a period no more than 18 months from the date of our last contact with you under the legal basis of Legitimate Interest.
This will allow us to respond to queries and uphold quotes within these periods.
No retained data will be used for any purpose other than that which is agreed at the time of booking and will never be shared with third-parties without your knowledge or used to contact you in future without requirement or your consent.
YOUR RIGHTS
If at any point you believe the information we process on you is incorrect or should you wish to withdraw your consent or exercise any of your statutory rights including your right to erasure, right to access, right to rectification and right to be informed, you can request to see this information and have it corrected or deleted.
If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal data, you can contact our team at privacy@rescuetech1.com who will investigate the matter and take the necessary actions.
CHILDREN
Rescue Technology will never request consent or market to anybody under the age of 16.
USING YOUR INFORMATION
We use the information that we collect from you to provide our services to you. In addition to this we may use the information for one or more of the following purposes:
To provide information to you that you request from us relating to our products or services.
To arrange delivery of goods or services as requested.
To provide information to you relating to other products that may be of interest to you. Such additional information will only be provided where you have consented to receive such information and you can withdraw consent at any time.
To inform you of any changes to our website, services or goods and products.
COOKIES
We employ cookie technology to help log visitors to our web site as well as to enable certain functions of our web services such as logging in to secure areas, storing your shopping cart information and processing registrations.
Cookies are pieces of data that are created when you visit a website, and which are stored in the cookie directory of your computer.
A number of cookies may be created when you visit Rescue Technology websites.
Most of these cookies do not contain any personal information about you, and they cannot be used to identify an individual user.
One of our cookies is used by a third-party company (Lead Forensics) in order to identify businesses using our site and to aid with future development of our website and analysis of website usage.
The data which is provided to us by Lead Forensics does not make it possible to identify an individual, solely a company and any registered details relating to it.
You can set your browser not to accept cookies. If you do not know how to do this, contact us, giving details on the type of browser you are using, and we will do our best to help.
Please note that if you do set your browser not to accept cookies some of the enhanced features on our website may not work correctly.
ANALYTICS
We use Google Analytics to store information about how visitors use our website so that we may make improvements and give visitors a better user experience.
Google Analytics is a third-party information storage system that records information about the pages you visit, the length of time you were on specific pages and the website in general, how you arrived at the site and what you clicked on when you were there. These cookies do not store any personal information about you eg name, address etc and we do not share the data. You can view their privacy policy below:
Google - http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/
LOG FILES
When you visit a Rescue Technology website, we collect web statistics concerning your visit which are stored in a log file. Log files allow us to record visitors’ use of the site as well as monitor site performance and address any errors. The web teams use analytics to record visitors’ use of the site and use this information to make changes to the layout of the website and to the information provided on the website.
Log files do not contain any personal information and they are not used to identify any individual patterns of use of the site.
This statement only covers websites and data maintained by Rescue Technology and does not cover other data or websites linked to or associated with our websites.
CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY STAEMENT
We may change our Privacy Statement from time to time in line with legislation and industry standards.
We will not be explicitly notifying all website users about these changes and therefore recommend that you check this statement occasionally for any policy changes.
Below is a change log of all revisions made.
Your cart is empty.
Home | About Us | Contact Us | My Account | Shipping Policy | Return Policy | Privacy Policy | Sitemap | Cart Help
Browse All Products
Rescue Technology, 251 Beulah Church Road, Carrollton, GA 30117
800-334-3368, 770-832-9694 Fax 770-832-1676
Copyright © 2003, 2004, 2005, 2006, 2007, 2008, 2009, 2010 Rescue Technology |Technical Rope Rescue Equipment
